[
    [
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This company briefly surpassed Apple as the most valuable public company in the world. The company, founded in 1993, initially focused on developing graphics processing units (GPUs) for the gaming market. However, it has since expanded its reach to include artificial intelligence, data centers, and autonomous vehicles. Its GPUs are now widely used in various fields, including scientific research, machine learning, and cryptocurrency mining. Name this company, headquartered in Santa Clara, California, known for its GeForce series of GPUs.",
            "answers": ["NVIDIA"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "In one contest, this figure asks Vafthruthnir about what he whispered in the ear of his son. This deity hung himself from Yggdrasil for nine days in order to learn about runes, and he uses the ravens Huginn and Muninn as messengers. This owner of the horse Sleipnir drank from the Well of Mimir in exchange for his eye. Identify this Norse \"All Father,\" the ruler of the gods, and father of Thor",
            "answers": ["Odin"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This infamous criminal gained notoriety during the Great Depression era for his daring bank robberies and multiple prison escapes. He was declared \"Public Enemy No. 1\" by the FBI and became a folk hero to some who admired his defiance of authority and his Robin Hood-like image. He was ultimately killed in a shootout with federal agents outside the Biograph Theater in Chicago in 1934. Name this notorious gangster whose exploits captivated the nation and solidified his place in American criminal lore.",
            "answers": ["John Dillinger", "Dilinger"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This team, one of the original NBA franchises, has a long and storied history, including a remarkable run of eight consecutive championships from 1959 to 1966 under legendary coach Red Auerbach. Led by Hall of Famers such as Bill Russell, Bob Cousy, and John Havlicek, they established themselves as a dominant force in the league. More recently, they reached the NBA Finals in 2022 and ultimately secured their 18th championship in 2024, led by Jayson Tatum and Jaylen Brown. Name this team that holds the record for the most NBA championships.",
            "answers": ["Boston Celtics", "Celtics"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "This object was described as a \"small cloud\" by Persian astronomer Abd al-Rahman al-Sufi in 964. It takes its name from the constellation in which it appears, which is named for the mythological wife of Perseus. This object is predicted to collide with the Milky Way in about five billion years. Name this member of the Local Group, the closest spiral galaxy to the Milky Way.",
            "answers": ["Andromeda", "andromena", " Andromeda galaxy"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "Gordon Sumner, known professionally by this stage name, rose to fame as the frontman, bassist, and principal songwriter of the new wave rock band The Police. After the band's breakup in 1986, he embarked on a successful solo career. He is known for his distinctive voice, socially conscious lyrics, and hits like \"Every Breath You Take,\" \"Englishman in New York,\" and \"Fields of Gold.\" Name this English musician who has sold over 100 million records worldwide.",
            "answers": ["Sting"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This heir presumptive to the Austro-Hungarian throne was assassinated in Sarajevo in June 1914. His death, at the hands of Gavrilo Princip, a Serbian nationalist, sparked a chain of events that led to the outbreak of World War I. Name this archduke whose assassination is considered a key catalyst for one of the deadliest conflicts in human history.",
            "answers": ["Franz Ferdinand"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This island nation, located in the Persian Gulf, is an archipelago consisting of 50 natural islands and an additional 33 artificial islands. It is connected to Saudi Arabia by the King Fahd Causeway, a 25-kilometer bridge, and is separated by a small section of a Persian Gulf from Qatar. This country is the third-smallest nation in Asia by area and is home an international circuit, which hosts an annual Formula One race. Name this country with its capital at Manama.",
            "answers": ["Bahrain"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "category": "Geography",
            "question": "This country's capital city was designed in the shape of an airplane around a \"Monumental Axis\" by architect Oscar Niemeyer. \"Cariocas\" are residents of this country's second most populous city, which was the origin of bossa nova music and hosts massive parades in the Sambodrome during Carnaval. Name this Portuguese-speaking country in South America which contains most of the Amazon rainforest.",
            "answers": ["Brazil"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Sports",
            "question": "This NHL team won their first Stanley Cup in franchise history in 2024, defeating the Edmonton Oilers in seven games after initially being up 3-0 in the series. The team lost to the Vegas Golden Knights in the Stanley Cup Finals in 2023. This team, founded in 1993 as an expansion franchise, experienced a Cinderella run to the Stanley Cup Finals in 1996, ultimately losing to the Colorado Avalanche. Name this NHL team based in Sunrise, Florida. ",
            "answers": ["Florida Panthers", "Panthers"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "US History",
            "question": "This law enforcement official served as the first Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), holding the position for 48 years under eight presidents. He is credited with modernizing the FBI and transforming it into a major crime-fighting agency, but his legacy is also controversial due to his use of surveillance and intimidation tactics against political activists and civil rights leaders. Name this influential figure in American law enforcement who remains a subject of debate and scrutiny.",
            "answers": [
                "J. Edgar Hoover",
                "Hoover",
                "J Hoover",
                "Edgar Hoover"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Entertainment",
            "question": "This coming-of-age drama film, directed by Barry Jenkins, tells the story of a young African-American man named Chiron as he grapples with his identity and sexuality while growing up in a rough Miami neighborhood. It garnered critical acclaim for its poignant storytelling, powerful performances, and exploration of themes such as masculinity, family, and self-discovery. Name this film that won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2017 after a dramatic mix-up during the live announcement, where \"La La Land\" was initially mistakenly declared the winner.",
            "answers": ["Moonlight"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Arts & Literature",
            "question": "A woman in this novel is fired from her factory job for having a child out of wedlock. The protagonist of this novel is given silver candlesticks by a bishop. Gavroche catches a police officer at a barricade in this novel, who kills himself after being mercifully freed. Eponine Thenardier saves the life of Marius in this novel. Name this novel about the ex-convict Jean Valjean by Victor Hugo.",
            "answers": ["Les Miserables", " Les miz"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "World History",
            "question": "This pharaoh, who ascended to the throne at the age of nine, reigned for only about a decade before his untimely death at around 19. His tomb, discovered in 1922 by Howard Carter in the Valley of the Kings, was remarkably intact, containing a wealth of treasures and artifacts that provided valuable insights into ancient Egyptian life and burial practices. Name this \"boy king\" whose tomb's discovery sparked a worldwide fascination with ancient Egypt.",
            "answers": [
                "Tutankhamun",
                "Tutankhamen",
                "King Tut",
                "Tutankhamuna",
                "King Tutankhamun",
                "King Tutankhamen"
            ],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Current Events",
            "question": "This prehistoric monument, constructed over multiple phases spanning centuries, features a circular ditch and bank, a ring of bluestones transported from Wales, and a horseshoe arrangement of massive sarsen stones. Its alignment with the sunrise on the summer solstice suggests a connection to solar events and possibly astronomical observations. Name this iconic megalithic structure located on Salisbury Plain in Wiltshire, England, a UNESCO World Heritage Site that continues to be a source of fascination and speculation.",
            "answers": ["Stonehenge"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        },
        {
            "category": "Science",
            "question": "These objects have a clinamen, or a tendency to swerve, as stated by Lucretius in On the Nature of Things. These objects have electron clouds, which are not represented in the Bohr model of them. Democritus believed that these objects made up everything in the universe. The Greek word for \"indivisible\" provided the name of what fundamental units of matter that can be combined into molecules?",
            "answers": ["atoms", " atom"],
            "used": "FALSE"
        }
    ]
]
